woodforest.com 2003-06-22

# Woodforest National Bank-Online Banking

Apply Now        
Find Out More   
|  |   
---|---  
| Privacy Policy  
| Online Banking Disclosure  
| Security Policy  
| Privacy Notice  
  |    
|   

|  |    

Privacy Policy

Overview

Woodforest National Bank recognizes that customer information is confidential and personal. As an organization, our management team takes specific steps to ensure the privacy of information about you and your account is protected. As an organization in the financial services industry, we recognize that privacy is critical, and the sensitivity to protecting information is continually growing with the expansion of electronic commerce. You may count on us to protect your information with a high level of security and appropriate discretion.

Woodforest National Bank has adopted specific personal data protection principles which detail our institution’s handling of personal information. We place a high priority on the confidentiality of customer information. It is our intent to protect information provided by you as our customer! 

We acknowledge that our bank collects, retains, and utilizes information about its customers where management deems it useful (and permitted by law) to further our business efforts. Information about our customers, for example, assists our staff in developing new or enhancing existing products and services, and thereafter, offering them to our customers.

Woodforest National Bank has established in-depth security standards and procedures to guard and protect customer information against unauthorized access. These controls and procedures are periodically reviewed and tested to ensure that these practices or processes serve our primary mission to protect confidential information. Further, management and staff are able to access personal confidential customer information only if and when they have a business reason to know.

On certain occasions, customer information may be provided to a third-party which has provided an appropriate reason to request such information. The third party receiving such information must adhere to the privacy principles that cover such information regarding confidentiality. Information disclosures to an independent third party regarding personal, confidential information or other personally identifiable data for that entity’s specific usage is not allowed except where the exchange occurs with a reputable information reporting agency. Information exchanges with reporting agencies is deemed important to maximize the accuracy and detail of information reported. In certain situations, information is provided as detailed in the following specific situations:

  1. Customer requests it;
  2. Per request of customer, data are provided to help complete a customer-approved transaction;
  3. Disclosure is required by/per law (e.g., court order, investigation, or fraudulent investigation);
  4. Customer has been informed, and has had the opportunity to approve/decline in prior written communication, the possibility of disclosure of information for marketing or similar purposes.

Statement of Data Protection Principles

  * We will not sell or provide personal information to third parties for independent use.
  * If we collect information about you from someone else, we will make sure you know we have done so, as soon as and wherever possible
  * We will only collect information which is necessary for performing bank business on your behalf
  * When and where practical, we will collect personal information directly from you 
  * We shall only use or disclose that information about you that is consistent with your directions and expectations, or is in the public interest (general banking loan and/or account relationship(s) and your performance per pre-agreed upon terms and/or conditions)
  * We will ensure that information about you is accurate when we collect or use it, to the best of our capabilities
  * We will keep information secure
  * Whenever possible, we will provide you with opportunities to see the personal information we hold for you and furthermore, we will explain what we do with it, and correct it if it is wrong
  * We will be open with you about what kinds of personal information we hold and what we do with it

If at any time you have a concern about your information security, you may contact us through [e-mail](mailto:info@woodforest.com) at [info@woodforest.com](mailto:info@woodforest.com), call our institution at 713-455-7000, or write us at   
Woodforest National Bank  
Information Privacy  
P.O. Box 24459  
Houston, TX 77015.

|
